Zoltan Domahidi

Hungary



domahidizoltan@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/domahidizoltan

Summary

I'm an experienced software engineer with 10+ years of backend development, 5+ years of distributed systems and 2+ years of Golang development experience. I help companies in building highly scalable cloud applications, being involved in the full lifecycle of the product. I have a focus on quality and knowledge sharing, while I also care about my professional growth. I'm mainly interested in distributed architectures, cloud, and Golang stacks.

Experience

Senior Backend Software Engineer / Golang Developer

CIRCL Technologies Ltd

Jan 2023 - Present (6 months)

- development and improvement of Proto Energy SaaS product
- building the WebSocket API for the event sourcing (and CQRS) based backend
- writing and maintaining end-to-end tests
- proposing code design improvements
- tech stack: Go / Golang, Postgres, Redis, RabbitMQ, WebSocket, AWS Lambda, AWS, Docker, Cucumber.is, TypeScript, Github

Senior Backend Software Engineer / Golang Developer

Alpaca

Jul 2021 - Jan 2023 (1 year 7 months)

- development and improvement of Alpaca's brokerage system; extracting some parts from the monolith application to new microservices
- scale the monthly statement generation and increase the job throughput by ~20x
- build the scalable backend for mobile app push notifications
- working on subscription management and payment related features
- tech stack: Microservices, Go / Golang, Postgres, RabbitMQ, gRPC, Testify, Iris, Kubernetes, Helm, Ansible, Google Cloud Platform, Github

Senior Backend Software Engineer / Kotlin Developer

Telekom HU

Apr 2019 - Jun 2021 (2 years 3 months)

- development of Telekom's Product Inventory system
- development of Community Engine which provides discounts for committed Telekom customers
- messaging, data auditing, testing, and CI related improvements
- supporting the team in technical design and decisions
- giving a presentation about Kotlin

- tech stack: Microservices, Kotlin, Spring Boot 2 (Webflux), Reactor, MongoDB, Kafka, MockK, Junit 5, JPA, RabbitMQ, TestContainers, Spring Cloud Stream (both RabbitMQ and Kafka), Kubernetes, Helm, Gradle, Git, GitLab

Senior Java Software Engineer / Technical Team Lead

Grape Solutions

Sep 2018 - Apr 2019 (8 months)

- development of Emobility, Hungary's electric car charging IoT platform
- making software architecture and technology decisions
- improving local development environment, code quality, and testability
- mentoring Java developers; giving presentations about TDD & Http-Mocking
- tech stack: Microservices, Java 11, Spring Boot 2 (Webflux), Reactor, Python, Junit5, JPA, Jooq, Wiremock, Testcontainers, GCP, Docker, Kubernetes, Istio, Gradle, Git



Senior Java Developer

Secret Sauce Partners

Apr 2018 - Sep 2018 (6 months)

- development and maintenance of Style-Finder, an apparel recommendation system
- tech stack: Java8, Dropwizard, Guice, Hibernate, PostgreSQL, Spring Boot, Kafka, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, Python, Avro, Maven, Git, Circle CI, JUnit 5, TDD, CleanCode

Senior Java Developer

evosoft

Nov 2014 - Apr 2018 (3 years 6 months)

- design and development of a cloud-based Industry 4.0 project for MindSphere, Siemens (stream processing)
- supporting Java technical interviews
- in-house presentations about Clean Code, TDD, Spring Integration, Spring XD, Redis, and ScalaJS
- tech stack: Microservices, Java 8, Spring Boot, JPA, Rest, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL, Redis, Spring Cloud (Netflix OSS), Spring DataFlow (+ Cloud Stream), Reactor, AWS, Terraform, Docker, Gradle, Git, GitLab CI, TDD, CleanCode, Swagger, RestDocs, JUnit, Mockito, CDC (Pact), BDD (Cucumber)

Education



🎒 Universitatea din Oradea

Engineer's degree, Computer Science 2003 - 2008

Skills

Microservices • Go (Programming Language) • Docker Products • Kubernetes • API Development • Cloud Applications • Java • Spring Boot • Test-Driven Development